Guide to the James Fenimore Cooper Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
James Fenimore Cooper Collection
1792-1976
1792-1894
YCAL MSS 415
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
18.57
(37 boxes) + 20 broadside folders, 5 art objects
The collection provides evidence of the personal and professional life of James Fenimore Cooper, and to a lesser degree, the Cooper family, between 1792 and 1976. The collection documents Cooper's writing career, service in the United States Navy, and travels through Europe, and consists of correspondence, writings, personal papers, legal and financial documents, clippings, artwork, and objects. As an author who was engaged in the process of printing and publishing his works, and who was deeply interested in copyright, Cooper's papers shed light on book production during the mid nineteenth-century.
Cooper, James Fenimore, 1789-1851
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of James Fenimore Cooper, Henry S. Fenimore Cooper, and Linn Fenimore Cooper, 1931-1965.
Other material came to the library in small quantities from various sources as indicated on individual folders.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Existence and Location of Copies
A portion of this collection is available on microfilm as identified on individual folders.
James Fenimore Cooper (1789-1851)
James Fenimore Cooper, American novelist, was born on September 15, 1789, to William and Elizabeth Fenimore Cooper in Burlington, New Jersey. Cooper attended Yale College from 1803 to 1805, but was expelled before receiving a degree. In 1806 he worked on a merchant vessel, the Sterling, in order to acquire experience necessary before joining the navy in 1808. He served in several posts, including midshipman, paymaster, and quartermaster. Cooper resigned from the navy shortly after he married Susan Augusta De Lancey in 1811. During the first years of their marriage the couple lived in Westchester County, Cooperstown (founded by Cooper's father), and New York City, and throughout this period Cooper was involved in a number of business ventures, including whaling. He published his first novel ( Precaution ) in 1820, which launched his career as an author of a number of novels, non-fiction, and travel books. Among Cooper's best known works are his historical novels, such as The Last of the Mohicans, The Pioneers, The Prairie, and The Spy, and nautical novels including The Pilot and Homeward Bound. In 1826 Cooper moved to Europe, which inspired his trilogy of European novels as well as several non-fiction travel accounts. He returned to the U.S. in 1833, and after a period in New York City, moved to the Cooper family home, Otsego Hall, in Cooperstown where he died in 1851.
Susan Augusta De Lancey, the third child of John Peter and Elizabeth Floyd De Lancey was born on January 28, 1792 in Mamaroneck, New York. Her siblings were Thomas James, Anne Charlotte, Caroline, and Edward. John Peter De Lancey was a former British army officer and the De Lanceys were a prominent New York family. Susan Cooper is credited with motivating her husband to become an author, by suggesting that he write a better novel when he criticized a book he was reading to her. At times she also acted as a proof reader for Cooper when he was unavailable to check page proofs. Susan De Lancey Cooper died in Cooperstown in 1852.
The Coopers had five children who lived into adulthood, their four daughters, Susan, Caroline, Anne, and Maria, and son, Paul. Susan Fenimore Cooper (1813-1894) served as her father's copyist and eventually as his literary executor. She worked closely with him during the writing process, and evidence of her involvement is traced in forewords she wrote for Household editions of her father's works (published between 1876 and 1884) as well as her articles "A Glance Backward" and "A Second Glance Backward" published in the Atlantic Monthly (1887). She also edited Papers and Pictures from the Writings of James Fenimore Cooper (1861). In turn, James Fenimore Cooper promoted his daughter's literary career; her books include: Elinor Wyllys; or, The Young Folk of Longbridge (1845), Rural Hours (1850), Rhyme and Reason of Country Life (1854), Rural Rambles (1854), and Mount Vernon: A Letter to the Children of America (1859).
Scope and Contents
The James Fenimore Cooper Collection provides evidence of the personal and professional life of James Fenimore Cooper, and to a lesser degree, the Cooper family, between 1792 and 1976. The papers chronicle Cooper's writing career, involvement in the navy, and travels through Europe, and consist of correspondence, writings, personal papers, legal and financial documents, clippings, artwork, and objects. As an author who was engaged in the process of printing and publishing his works, as well as in establishing and protecting his own copyright, Cooper's papers shed light on book production during the mid-nineteenth century.
James Fenimore Cooper's creative process can be traced in the collection, which contains documents from various stages in producing a work, ranging from notebooks and research material to handwritten drafts, proofs, printed versions, and reviews. Cooper gained a reputation during his lifetime, and evidence of his fame can be found in correspondents requesting his autograph, letters inviting him to lecture, various articles about him and his home, Otsego Hall, engraved portraits, and correspondence with Horatio Greenough, who sculpted a bust of Cooper (an image of which can be found in the Art Series). However, Cooper's fame also impacted the preservation of his literary manuscripts, pages of which were often dispersed to various collectors and autograph seekers; for this reason many of his drafts have missing sections. Material objects reflecting Cooper's profession as a writer, such as his travel desk and desk set, are also part of the collection.
James Fenimore Cooper was keenly aware and protective of his legal rights. His interest in copyright is evident in his correspondence with his printers and publishers, such as his care in establishing copyright in the U.S. and England and his concern when pirated works appeared of his novels. He kept detailed notes about copyright ownership found in his "Copy Right Book" (1842) and was in possession of a pamphlet on "An Act to Amend the Laws Relating to Dramatic Literary Property" (1833). Cooper also held the copyright for Susan Fenimore Cooper's publication Rural Hours, and his family filed for copyright ownership of a number of Cooper's works following his death. In many ways Cooper's interest in copyright reflects the financial realities of his career as an author, as can be traced in various financial documents in the collection.
Between 1839 and 1845 Cooper was also involved in a number of legal proceedings, most notably libel cases filed against publishers, such as Park Benjamin ( The New World ), Horace Greeley and Thomas McElrath ( New York Tribune ), William L. Stone ( Commercial Advertiser ), Thurlow Weed ( Evening Journal ), and James Watson Webb ( Courier and Enquirer ). As various clippings in the collection indicate, these cases received extensive press coverage.
Cooper's career in the navy is evidenced by warrants appointing Cooper midshipman, paymaster, and quartermaster. As an author he maintained an interest in maritime topics, which can be seen in his work to write The History of the Navy of the United States of America, seafaring-themed novels such as The Pilot and The Water Witch, and several articles for The Naval Magazine. He also corresponded with a number of naval officers such as William Branford Shubrick and Charles Wilkes, as well as Ned Myers (who inspired Ned Myers: A Life Before the Mast ). After leaving the navy Cooper was briefly involved in whaling, which is chronicled in his correspondence with partner Charles T. Dering and an account book for the whaling vessel Union.
Cooper served as the American consul in Lyons, France, and lived in Europe for seven years. A letter appointing Cooper to this position, signed by John Quincy Adams, is included in the collection, along with other items relating to the family's move to Europe, such as visas, travel documents, a passport, and calling cards. This period is also reflected in Cooper's correspondence with the Marquis de Lafayette and William Cabell Rives. While living in Europe, Cooper fostered relationships with publishers, such as Charles Gosselin in France and Duncker & Humblot in Germany, who published translations of his novels.
Cooper's family life can be traced in his correspondence with his wife and children, as well as with extended family members. In addition, the family's everyday life can be glimpsed through their financial records, documenting the purchase of household items. In his diaries, which largely date from 1832 to 1835 in the collection, Cooper discusses his activities and opinions, including his experience of reading various chapters in the Bible. Because the Coopers, and their relatives the De Lanceys, Phinneys, and Pomeroys, were prominent American families, the collection is a window into social and political life during the nineteenth century. Cooper's correspondents include Daniel D. Barnard, Charles Jared Ingersoll, Joseph Reed Ingersoll, and John Jay (and his sons Peter A. and William), and Samuel F. B. Morse.
Arrangement
Organized into four series: I. Correspondence, 1813-1894; II. Writings, 1824-1976; III. Personal Papers, 1792-1975; and IV. Art and Objects, 1830-1854.
Appendix A: Former Call Number Reference
The index below provides a cross reference from the catalogue card numbers, noted as —#, to the current location of the same material in the present arrangement.
1 Box 14, folder 383
2 Box 14, folder 384
3 Box 14, folder 385-388
4 Box 15, folder 389-390
5 Box 19, folder 445
6 Box 16, folder 391
8 Box 17, folder 392
9 Box 17, folder 399-407
10 Box 17, folder 408
11 Box 18, folder 409-410
12 Box 18, folder 412
13 Box 20, folders 446-447
14 Box 18, folder 414
15 Box 18, folder 428
16 Box 18, folders 429-430
17 Box 20, folder 449
18 Box 18, folder 431
19 Box 19, folder 433
20 Box 19, folder 434
21 Box 19, folder 435
22 Box 19, folder 436
23 Box 19, folders 441-442
24 Box 26, folder 505
25 Box 27, folder 514
26 Box 23, folder 480
27 Box 32, folder 481
28 Box 23, folder 483
29 Box 23, folder 484
30 Box 23, folder 485
31 Box 23, folders 482
32 Box 17, folder 394
33 Box 17, folder 395
34 Box 1, folder 7
35 Box 1, folders 14-21
36 Box 1, folders 14-21
37 Box 2, folder 43
38 Box 2, folder 45
39 Box 5, 127-128
40 Box 5, 127-128
41 Box 13, folder 371
42 Box 11, folder 305
43 Box 12, folder 324
44 Box 13, folder 355
45 Box 12, folders 327-333
46 Box 3, folders 73-74
47 Box 3, folder 75
48 Box 3, folder 78
49 Box 3, folder 80
50 Box 4, folder 97
51 Box 3, folder 109
52 Box 2, folder 37
53 Box 5, folder 123
54 Box 5, folder 132
55 Box 5, folder 146
57 Box 7, folder 173
58 Box 7, folder 199
59 Box 7, folder 202
60 Box 8, folder 214
61 Box 8, folder 235
62 Box 10, folder 283
63 Box 20, folder 455
64 Box 20, folder 451
65 Box 20, folder 452
66 Box 17, folder 397
67 Box 20, folder 457
68 Box 20, folder 456
69 Box 27, folder 517
70 Box 20, folder 459
71 Box 20, folder 458
73 Box 18, folder 413
76 Box 17, folder 393
77 Box 19, folder 444
78 Box 24, folder 486
79 Box 17, folder 397
80 Box 27, folder 513
81 Box 18, folder 412
82 Box 17, folder 398
83 Box 19, folder 443
84 Box 24, folders 487-488
85 Box 24, folder 489
86 Box 24, folders 490-491
88 Box 24, folder 492
89 Box 24, folder 493
90 Box 24, folder 494
91 Box 24, folder 495
92 Box 25, folders 496-499
93 Box 25, folder 500
94 Box 25, folder 501-502
95 Box 25, folder 503
96 Box 25, folder 504
97 Box 26, folders 506-509
98 Box 26, folder 510
99 Box 1, folder 2
100 Box 1, folder 3
105 Box 1, folder 5
106 Box 1, folder 6
106b Box 1, folder 7
107 Box 1, folder 8
109 Box 1, folder 9
110 Box 1, folder 10
111 Box 1, folder 11
112 Box 1, folder 12
117 Box 1, folders 14-21
118 Box 1, folder 13
119 Box 1, folder 22
124 Box 1, folder 23
125 Box 1, folder 24
127 Box 1, folder 26
128 Box 1, folder 27
129 Box 5, folder 129
130 Box 1, folder 28
131 Box 1, folder 29
133 Box 1, folder 30
135 Box 1, folder 31
140 Box 1, folder 32
144 Box 2, folder 33
145 Box 2, folder 33
146 Box 2, folder 33
147 Box 2, folder 33
148 Box 2, folders 34-36
149 Box 2, folders 34-36
150 Box 2, folder 33
151 Box 2, folder 33
152 Box 2, folder 38
153 Box 2, folder 39
154 Box 2, folder 33
155 Box 2, folder 40
156 Box 2, folder 41
157 Box 2, folder 42
158 Box 2, folder 44
159 Box 2, folder 45
160 Box 2, folder 33
161 Box 2, folder 33
162 Box 2, folder 33
163 Box 2, folder 46
164 Box 2, folder 33
165 Box 5, folders 127-128
166 Box 5, folders 127-128
167 Box 5, folders 127-128
168 Box 2, folder 48
169 Box 2, folder 49
170 Box 2, folder 50
171 Box 2, folder 33
172 Box 2, folder 52
173 Box 2, folder 33
174 Box 2, folder 33
175 Box 2, folder 54
180 Box 3, folder 60
181 Box 3, folder 61
182 Box 3, folder 61
183 Box 3, folder 63
184 Box 3, folder 64
185 Box 3, folder 65
186 Box 3, folder 66
187 Box 3, folder 67
188 Box 2, folder 51
189 Box 9, folder 249
190 Box 2, folder 33
191 Box 2, folder 33
192 Box 2, folder 33
193 Box 3, folder 68
194 Box 2, folder 33
195 Box 3, folder 69
196 Box 2, folder 33
197 Box 2, folder 33
198 Box 2, folder 33
199 Box 3, folder 70
200 Box 3, folder 70
201 Box 3, folder 70
202 Box 3, folders 70-71
203 Box 3, folder 70
204 Box 3, folder 70
205 Box 3, folder 72
206 Box 3, folders 73-74
207 Box 3, folder 76
208 Box 3, folder 77
209 Box 3, folder 79
210 Box 3, folder 80
211 Box 3, folder 81
212 Box 3, folder 82
213 Box 3, folder 83
214 Box 3, folder 84
215 Box 3, folder 70
216 Box 3, folder 70
217 Box 3, folder 70
218 Box 3, folder 70
219 Box 3, folder 85
220 Box 3, folder 86
221 Box 3, folder 70
222 Box 3, folder 70
223 Box 3, folder 70
224 Box 3, folder 70
225 Box 3, folder 70
226 Box 3, folder 70
227 Box 3, folder 70
228 Box 3, folder 87
229 Box 3, folder 88
230 Box 4, folder 89
231 Box 3, folder 70
232 Box 3, folder 70
233 Box 4, folder 92
234 Box 4, folder 93
235 Box 4, folders 94-95
236 Box 4, folders 94-95
237 Box 4, folders 94-95
242 Box 4, folder 97
243 Box 4, folder 97
244 Box 4, folder 98
247 Box 4, folder 99
249 Box 4, folders 100-101
252 Box 4, folder 102
255 Box 3, folder 104
256 Box 4, folder 105
257 Box 4, folder 106
258 Box 4, folder 107
259 Box 4, folder 108
260 Box 4, folder 110
261 Box 4, folder 107
262 Box 4, folder 111
263 Box 4, folder 112
264 Box 5, folder 113
265 Box 4, folder 107
266 Box 4, folder 107
267 Box 4, folder 107
268 Box 4, folder 107
269 Box 4, folder 107
270 Box 4, folder 107
271 Box 5, folder 114
272 Box 4, folder 107
273 Box 4, folder 107
274 Box 4, folder 107
275 Box 5, folder 115
276 Box 5 folder 116
277 Box 4, folder 119
278 Box 5, folders 117-118
279 Box 5, folder 120
280 Box 5, folder 121
281 Box 5, folders 117-118
282 Box 5, folder 122
283 Box 5, folders 117-118
284 Box 5, folder 123
285 Box 5, folder 124
286 Box 5, folder 126
287 Box 5, folders 117-118
288 Box 5, folders 117-118
289 Box 5, folders 117-118
290 Box 5, folder 126
291 Box 5, folders 117-118
292 Box 5, folders 117-118
293 Box 5, folders 117-118
294 Box 5, folders 117-118
295 Box 5, folders 117-118
296 Box 5, folders 117-118
297 Box 5, folders 117-118
298 Box 5, folders 117-118
299 Box 5, folders 117-118
300 Box 5, folders 117-118
302 Box 5, folder 130
303 Box 5, folders 117-118
304 Box 5, folders 117-118
305 Box 5, folders 117-118
306 Box 5, folders 117-118
307 Box 5, folders 117-118
308 Box 5, folders 117-118
309 Box 5, folders 117-118
310 Box 5, folder 131
311 Box 5, folders 117-118
312 Box 5, folders 117-118
313 Box 5, folder 133
314 Box 5, folder 134
315 Box 5, folder 135
316 Box 5, folder 136
317 Box 5, folder 137
318 Box 5, folder 138
319 Box 5, folder 139
320 Box 5, folder 141
321 Box 5, folder 142
322 Box 5, folders 143-144
323 Box 5, folder 145
324 Box 5, folder 140
325 Box 5, folder 140
326 Box 5, folder 146
327 Box 5, folder 140
328 Box 5, folder 140
329 Box 5, folder 140
330 Box 5, folder 140
331 Box 5, folder 148
332 Box 6, folder 150
333 Box 5, folder 149
334 Box 5, folder 149
335 Box 6, folder 151
336 Box 5, folder 149
337 Box 5, folder 149
338 Box 5, folder 149
339 Box 6, folder 153
340 Box 6, folders 156-159
341 Box 6, folder 154
342 Box 6, folder 155
343 Box 6, folders 156-159
344 Box 6, folder 152
345 Box 6, folder 152
346 Box 6, folder 152
347 Box 6, folder 152
348 Box 6, folder 160
349 Box 6, folder 152
350 Box 6, folder 152
351 Box 6, folder 152
352 Box 6, folder 152
353 Box 6, folder 152
354 Box 6, folder 152
355 Box 6, folder 152
356 Box 6, folder 152
357 Box 6, folder 152
358 Box 6, folder 152
359 Box 6, folder 152
360 Box 6, folder 162
361 Box 6, folder 152
362 Box 6, folder 163
363 Box 6, folder 152
364 Box 8, folders 216-218
365 Box 6, folder 152
366 Box 6, folder 164
367 Box 6, folder 165-167
369 Box 6, folder 165-167
370 Box 6, folder 165-167
371 Box 6, folder 165-167
372 Box 6, folder 165-167
373 Box 6, folder 165-167
374 Box 6, folder 168
375 Box 6, folder 165-167
376 Box 6, folder 165-167
377 Box 6, folder 165-167
378 Box 6, folder 165-167
379 Box 6, folder 165-167
380 Box 6, folder 165-167
381 Box 6, folder 169
382 Box 6, folder 165-167
383 Box 6, folder 165-167
384 Box 6, folder 170
385 Box 6, folder 171
386 Box 6, folder 165-167
387 Box 6, folder 165-167
388 Box 6, folder 165-167
391 Box 7, folder 172
392 Box 6, folder 165-167
393 Box 6, folder 165-167
394 Box 6, folder 165-167
395 Box 5, folders 117-118
396 Box 7, folder 173
397 Box 6, folder 165-167
398 Box 7, folder 174
399 Box 6, folder 165-167
400 Box 6, folder 165-167
401 Box 7, folder 175
402 Box 6, folder 165-167
403 Box 7, folder 176
404 Box 6, folder 165-167
405 Box 7, folder 177
407 Box 6, folder 165-167
408 Box 7, folder 178
409 Box 7, folder 179
410 Box 7, folder 180
411 Box 7, folder 180
412 Box 7, folder 180
413 Box 7, folder 180
414 Box 7, folder 180
415 Box 7, folder 180
416 Box 7, folder 181
417 Box 7, folder 180
418 Box 7, folder 183
419 Box 7, folder 182
420 Box 7, folders 184-186
421 Box 7, folder 421
422 Box 7, folder 188
423 Box 7, folder 190
423a Box 7, folder 189
424 Box 7, folder 182
425 Box 7, folder 191
426 Box 7, folder 182
427 Box 7, folder 182
428 Box 7, folders 192-193
429 Box 7, folder 194
430 Box 7, folders 192-193
431 Box 7, folders 192-193
432 Box 7, folders 192-193
433 Box 7, folders 192-193
433b Box 7, folders 192-193
434 Box 7, folders 192-193
435 Box 7, folders 192-193
436 Box 7, folder 195
437 Box 7, folders 192-193
438 Box 7, folders 192-193
439 Box 7, folders 192-193
440 Box 7, folder 196
441 Box 7, folder 197
442 Box 7, folder 198
443 Box 7, folders 192-193
444 Box 7, folders 192-193
445 Box 7, folders 192-193
446 Box 7, folder 199
447 Box 7, folder 199
448 Box 6, folder 165-167
449 Box 7, folder 200
450 Box 7, folders 192-193
451 Box 7, folder 201
452 Box 7, folder 202
453 Box 7, folders 192-193
454 Box 7, folders 192-193
455 Box 7, folder 203
456 Box 7, folders 192-193
457 Box 7, folder 204
458 Box 7, folder 205
459 Box 7, folder 206
460 Box 7, folders 192-193
461 Box 7, folder 207
462 Box 8, folder 208
463 Box 8, folder 209-210
464 Box 8, folder 208
465 Box 8, folder 211
466 Box 8, folder 208
467 Box 8, folder 208
468 Box 8, folder 208
469 Box 8, folder 208
470 Box 8, folder 208
471 Box 8, folder 208
472 Box 8, folder 208
473 Box 8, folder 208
474 Box 8, folder 208
475 Box 8, folder 208
476 Box 8, folder 208
477 Box 8, folder 208
478 Box 8, folder 212
479 Box 8, folder 213
480 Box 8, folder 208
481 Box 8, folder 208
483 Box 8, folder 208
484 Box 8, folder 208
485 Box 8, folder 208
486 Box 8, folder 208
487 Box 8, folder 208
488 Box 8, folder 208
489 Box 8, folder 215
490 Box 8, folders 216-218
491 Box 8, folders 216-218
492 Box 8, folders 216-218
493 Box 8, folders 216-218
494 Box 8, folders 216-218
495 Box 8, folders 216-218
496 Box 8, folders 216-218
497 Box 8, folders 216-218
498 Box 8, folders 216-218
499 Box 8, folders 216-218
500 Box 8, folders 216-218
501 Box 8, folders 216-218
502 Box 8, folders 219
503 Box 8, folder 221
504 Box 8, folder 222
505 Box 8, folders 223-229
506 Box 8, folder 230
507 Box 8, folder 231
508 Box 8, folders 216-218
509 Box 8, folders 216-218
510 Box 8, folders 216-218
511 Box 8, folders 216-218
512 Box 8, folders 216-218
513 Box 8, folders 216-218
514 Box 8, folder 232
515 Box 8, folders 216-218
516 Box 8, folders 216-218
517 Box 8, folders 216-218
519 Box 8, folders 216-218
520 Box 8, folders 216-218
521 Box 8, folders 216-218
522 Box 8, folder 233
523 Box 8, folders 216-218
525 Box 8, folder 234
526 Box 8, folders 216-218
527 Box 8, folders 216-218
528 Box 8, folders 216-218
529 Box 8, folders 216-218
530 Box 9, folder 237
531 Box 8, folders 216-218
532 Box 8, folders 216-218
533 Box 9, folder 238
534 Box 9, folder 239
535 Box 8, folders 216-218
536 Box 8, folders 216-218
537 Box 8, folders 216-218
538 Box 8, folders 216-218
539 Box 9, folder 240
540 Box 9, folder 241
541 Box 8, folders 216-218
542 Box 9, folder 242
543 Box 9, folder 243
544 Box 8, folders 216-218
545 Box 9, folder 244
546 Box 9, folder 246
547 Box 9, folder 245
548 Box 9, folder 247
549 Box 9, folder 245
550 Box 9, folder 248
551 Box 9, folder 245
552 Box 9, folder 245
553 Box 9, folder 245
554 Box 9, folder 245
555 Box 9, folder 245
556 Box 9, folder 245
557 Box 9, folder 245
558 Box 9, folder 245
559 Box 9, folder 245
560 Box 9, folder 245
561 Box 9, folder 245
562 Box 9, folder 250
563 Box 9, folder 245
564 Box 9, folder 245
565 Box 9, folder 251
566 Box 9, folder 252
567 Box 9, folder 253
568 Box 9, folder 254
569 Box 9, folder 255
570 Box 9, folder 256
571 Box 9, folders 257-259
572 Box 9, folders 257-259
573 Box 9, folders 257-259
574 Box 9, folder 261
575 Box 9, folders 257-259
576 Box 9, folders 257-259
577 Box 9, folders 257-259
578 Box 9, folders 257-259
579 Box 9, folders 257-259
581 Box 9, folders 257-259
582 Box 9, folder 263
583 Box 9, folder 264
584 Box 9, folders 257-259
585 Box 9, folders 257-259
586 Box 9, folders 257-259
587 Box 9, folders 257-259
588 Box 9, folder 265
589 Box 9, folders 257-259
590 Box 9, folder 267
591 Box 9, folder 266
592 Box 9, folders 257-259
593 Box 9, folders 257-259
594 Box 9, folders 257-259
595 Box 9, folder 269
596 Box 9, folders 257-259
598 Box 9, folders 257-259
599 Box 9, folders 257-259
600 Box 9, folders 257-259
601 Box 9, folders 257-259
602 Box 9, folders 257-259; box 10, folder 271
603 Box 9, folders 257-259
604 Box 9, folders 257-259
605 Box 10, folder 272
606 Box 9, folders 257-259
607 Box 3, folder 62
608 Box 2, folder 55
609 Box 2, folder 56
612 Box 10, folders 280-281
613 Box 10, folders 273-274
614 Box 10, folder 275
615 Box 10, folder 282
616 Box 10, folder 276
617 Box 10, folder 278
618 box 29, folders 535-537
619 Box 10, folder 279
620 Box 1, folder 31; box 4, folder 104; box 13, folder 374-375, 382
621 Box 17, folder 396
622 Box 29, folder 538
623 Box 7, folder 180
624 Box 27, folder 513
625 Box 27, folder 515
626 Box 26, folder 511; box 29, folders 533-534
627 Box 19, folder 439; box 27. folders 516, 518-523
628 Box 27, folders 519-523, box 29, folders 531-532
629 Box 20, folder 461
630 Box 1, folder 25
631 Box 1, folder 28
632 Box 1, folder 28
633 Box 2, folders 34-36
636 Box 20, folder 453
637 Box 17, folder 392
638 Box 19, folder 438
640 Box 13, folder 349
642 Box 11, folder 302
644 Box 11, folder 303
645 Box 2, folder 645; box11, foldeer 304
648 Box 10, folder 284
650 Box 2, folder 47
651 Box 3, folder 60; box 11, folder 289; box 13, folder 334
652 Box 11, folder 306
653 Box 29, folder 539
654 Box 11, folder 290, 301, 307; box 13, folder 342, 346, 371; box 29, folder 540
655 Box 13, folders 338-339
656 Box 3, folder 64; box 11, folder 291, 308; box 12, folders 322-323; box 13, folder 335, 350, 356, 358, 359; box 29, folder 539
657 Box 11. 308
659 Box 3, folder 65; box 13, folder 370